The next question is whether alpha beta can work with multi-player games.
下一个问题是 alpha-beta 剪枝算法能否应用于多人游戏
&gt;&gt; Well according to a paper by Korff, pruning can work as long as sum of
根据 Korff 写的论文 剪枝算法是能用的
the values the players' evaluation functions has an upper bound and
只要玩家评估函数返回值总和有上限
each player's value, you have lower bound.
且各玩家的分值有下限即可
&gt;&gt; Well for our number of mine moves evaluation function for isolation zero
对于我们为孤立棋创建的评估函数 #my_moves
is a natural lower bound, but what would make a good upper bound for the sum?
0 是个自然而然的下限 但总和要设什么上限好呢？
&gt;&gt; If an evaluation function could estimate the number of total moves
如果评估函数能估计
remaining for each player, it would work because the sum of the number of total
各玩家剩余的总步数 那就可以了 因为剩余步数总和
moves should not exceed the number of empty squares of the isolation board.
肯定不超过孤立棋盘的空格数的
For example, with this board, the limit should be 22 or around 7 per player.
比如 在这个棋盘里 上限应该是 22 也就是每个玩家的上限约为 7
&gt;&gt; That's fine in theory but
理论是说得通
but the upper bound would change with each level of the game tree.
但博弈树每层的上限都会变化
Can't we simplify things for illustration purposes?
为讲解方便 我们能不能把事情简化一下呢？
&gt;&gt; Okay, we'll say that the sum of players' scores can't exceed ten and,
好的 假设玩家总分值不能超过 10
to make things even easier, we'll say that the sum has to equal exactly ten.
再简化一下好了 假设总分值就是 10
&gt;&gt; And that's going to allow pruning?
这就能进行剪枝了？
&gt;&gt; Yep.
对的
And we'll show you an example that allows both immediate pruning and
我们来看一个例子 这个例子既涉及直接剪枝
shallow pruning.
又涉及浅层剪枝
&gt;&gt; Does that mean we can't do deep pruning like before?
这是不是意味着我们不能像之前一样进行深层剪枝了？
&gt;&gt; Unfortunately that's correct.
很遗憾 是的
While some pruning is possible,
虽然可以进行一些剪枝操作
deep pruning like what alpha beta allowed before isn't possible.
但如 alpha-beta 算法允许的深度剪枝是不行了
&gt;&gt; Okay so show me an example of immediate pruning.
好吧 让我看看直接剪枝的例子
Let's look at the left most bottom branch of the search tree.
我们来看看搜索树底层最左边的分支
Since we know that the maximum value is ten there is no point in evaluating
我们已经知道 最大值是 10 所以没有必要再评估
the next two branches to the right.
右边两个相邻的分支了
They can return at most ten and we already have that option.
因为它们最多也就能返回 10 而我们已经有 10 了
We can safely ignore them and propagate the values of the tree.
所以我们大可以忽略它们 把分值往树上传递
&gt;&gt; Great.
好极了
And I guess we can put limits on what values will be at the top most node.
我想 我们还可以给最上面的节点分值设限
However, in this case it doesn't help.
但在这里并没有什么意义
The value of player one could be anywhere from zero to ten.
玩家 1 的值会在 0 和 10 之间
The other ones will be less than ten.
其它玩家的值则会小于 10
&gt;&gt; But the middle branch would limit things a bit and
但中间的分支会造成一些限制的
we will see an example of shallow pruning for the right branch.
右边的分支就需要用到浅层剪枝
At the bottom level of the middle branch,
在中间这个分支的最底层
player two will pick the left most option.
玩家 2 会选择最左边的分支
Now we see player one will have a value greater than or equal to three.
现在我们知道玩家 1 的值会大于或等于 3
And since the sum has to be ten,
而由于总和是 10
each of the others are limited to values less than or equal to seven.
所以其它两个玩家的分值分别被限制在 7 或以下
&gt;&gt; But in the next branch over, player two will get a seven or better.
但在旁边这个分支里 玩家 2 会有一个 7 或大于 7 的值
Which means that player one will get a three or less.
这就意味着玩家 1 会得到等于或小于 3 的值
Since we already have a three, we can prune this last branch.
由于我们已经有 3 了 所以我们可以把最后这个分支剪掉
It's values will not matter,
它是什么值都无关紧要了
because we're going to choose the option we already have.
因为我们会选择已有的值
&gt;&gt; Now you see it.
你已经明白其中关节了
Let's have a quiz and work another example.
我们来做做练习 看看另一个例子吧